{"_id": "8bfe88db", "question": "How do I take care of a person who suffered stroke disease?", "answers": "It is lovely that you want to learn. Speak with the doctor and therapists about specific precautions.\nRemove throw rugs and clear the floor of things one might trip on. Install hand rails around stairs and grab bars in the bathroom/shower/toilet.\nEncourage him/her to do whatever s/he can do safely. Falling is common and can cause serious injury because normal reflexes to protect the head don’t always kick in. Another brain injury could cause further damage.\nFind tools that help the person be independent. For example, a “rocker knife” will let him/her cut food with one hand, so s/he doesn’t need someone to cut his/her food into bite sized pieces.\nRecovery will continue for the rest of his/her life if s/he continues to work on improving and if s/he is permitted to try. I climbed six storeys on Saturday because the elevator was out of service. My husband had said “you can’t do that” but I could and I did. I held tightly to the rail and took a break on the last landing to regain my breath, but I made it.\nGive them time to master skills — don’t assume they can’t do something just because they are awkward initially. We are survivors not victims."}
{"_id": "96618351", "question": "Is it really true that blood groups other than O type are more prone to heart attack and heart/stroke diseases?", "answers": "There is an association with heart disease and non-O+/- blood groups. The exact reasons are not known, so causation has not been established. The increased risk is less than 10%.\nYour Blood Type Could Be Linked to a Higher Risk of Heart Attack or\nStroke"}
{"_id": "5897ceb0", "question": "What are some useful tips for living a normal life with Stroke DISEASE?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1f6f473a", "question": "Is stroke linked to Alzheimer's disease?", "answers": "No, strokes don’t cause Alzheimer’s.\nHowever, Alzheimer’s is just one type of dementia, and there are quite a few other types, with the largest being “mixed”, or Alzheimer’s and something else. And what a stroke can do- besides causing dementia, itself- is speed up the damage going on in the brain when any kind of dementia is already present.\nAnd, keep in mind it is thought Alzheimer’s is “present” but undiagnosed because it just hasn’t gotten to the point it is interfering with life, up to ten years before such interference, so that, a stroke in that ten or-so year period can make it seem it was the cause of Alzheimer’s. It likely wasn’t; it just sped up the damage.\nAvoiding a stroke is one of the top five ways to avoid any dementia. Doesn’t mean no-stroke-no-dementia, just that stroke is, itself indicted in some forms of dementia."}
{"_id": "f70392c5", "question": "Can you get a stroke from having aortic valve disease?", "answers": "Yes but that depends on what sort of aortic arch “disease” your talking about. If it’s a congenital coarctation malformation,Aortic stenosis, aneurism or aortic stricture it can cause areas of restricted or pooled blood flow. Technically yes anytime you slow dwell time in blood vessels tiny emboli can develop. In the case of the Aorta it can cause emboli to get thrown up the carotid artery and cause strokes (Aka emboli or embolic showers) in the brain. Often if this is discovered it’s highly recommended to take long term anticoagulants. Surgery or minimal invasive procedures are often recommended.\nI want to stress that although concerning, this kind of disease can be well monitored managed and followed up on. You may need to see one or more specialists. Find a good health provider doctor,nurse practitioner or physicians assistant and start with a full health physical H&P (history and physical exam) People can live long relatively healthy lives with Aortic arch problems."}
{"_id": "ce41cff1", "question": "What are the exercises to prevent heart disease and stroke?", "answers": "Sometimes, muscle mass exercise, aerobic exercise, and lung health can greatly effect the health of the heart.\nThe health of the heart, is related to the lungs.\nExercise, aerobic exercises of all sorts, promotes the formation of capillaries, and vessels and additional blood supplies through vessels that only happens through stress and exercise that promote the formation of.\nSome of those of outside capillaries that can grow and give vessels to supply oxygen to the heart muscle. (On the outside of the heart muscles to provide capillaries and then oxygen)\nExercise can spur that in the body.\nHeart disease is a lot of things, genetics, and damages, many things not under the control of the individual.\nThe heart muscle cells, not not regenerate, so things that had and adverse effect, the heart muscles and cells does not recover or regenerate.\nExercise, can create or spur other capalery effect on the outside of the heart muscle to feed them, with good nutrition and exercise.\nA very slight affect, but real effect, to feed the existing heat cells, with oxygen through capalery growth.\nAerobic activity, and types of exercises stresses the system and stimulates the body to produce capillaries, to create new ones to feed organs like, such as the heart muscle."}
{"_id": "7dee9681", "question": "What can I do to reduce my risk of heart disease and stroke?", "answers": "See , if u have hypertension or high cholesterol , feel angina pain in chest where heart is situated , than better take necessary precautions by doing pranayaam that is breathing exercises in yoga and do it properly looking in u tube , do it regularly , but before that 40 min of warm up exercises at home is must and do it gently according to your age , physiological status …..u can take advice of some yoga experts….\nHave light , nutritious , delicious diet full of vitamins and minerals , but eat little less , eat little 4 times so that it will not put pressure in your heart , oil and salt are enemies of heart so avoid having oily spicey , junk food , alcohol , smoking , stress , over burden of work at home .\nEat less salt and sugar , have fruits but wash them properly with water , have lot of oranges , lemon juice water in empty stomach in morning , maintain hygiene , have liquid diet , no overeating of food ….all these factors will help to maintain your health. Get check your bp level and sugar levels if possible . And u can take advice from doctor too in phone . Some people having cardiac problems on doctor's advice keep sorbitol or aspirin at home if u feel severe pain keep one of these under your tongue , but take doctor's advice first , i am not doctor so i can't advise u …..\nHence quality food and physical exercises , meditation help to cope up with such problems….Thank you……"}
{"_id": "98a44230", "question": "I want to try the paleo diet, but it claims that potatoes are bad—and doesn't red meat cause strokes and other diseases?", "answers": "While many on the paleo diet do not eat potatoes, many certainly do. Often the level of starches/carbs is based on someone's goals and activity levels. Higher levels of activity = higher carb intake. Sweet potatoes and white rice are usually the go-tos but white potatoes have their place as well. Additionally there is evidence that white potatoes in the form of resistant starch\ncan be beneficial for gut bacteria.\nAs for red meat causing diseases (as many others have pointed out) this is nonsense. Don't determine your diet by what the headlines say is the latest superfood or what food is going to kill you. Its bullshit. Do your homework.\nThe paleo diet has never been about re-enactment, its a framework for living an optimal life based on human appropriate food, movement, sleep, etc. Over the past few years, the \"paleo diet\" has evolved to be more about real, whole foods than the previous strict dogma. Many folks have started including beans, potatoes, etc. based on their tolerance to these foods and overall health goals.\nFind out what works for you and don't get hung up on the minutiae."}
{"_id": "5c310b31", "question": "Can intermittent fasting prevent heart diseases and strokes?", "answers": "There is a growing body of evidence showing it can reduce the risks of a number of ailments.\nHowever, these studies are not perfect - they have their own limitations, including limited sample sizes, high dropout rates among study participants, as well as debates over exactly how intermittent fasting should be done in order to reap measurable benefits.\nKey sources to explore:\nNot so fast: Pros and cons of the newest diet trend - Harvard Health\nFasting boosts stem cells’ regenerative capacity\nIntermittent fasting - healthy or hype? | American Society for Nutrition\nIntermittent fasting promotes adipose thermogenesis and metabolic homeostasis via VEGF-mediated alternative activation of macrophage"}
{"_id": "4034fbcd", "question": "Is stroke a hereditary disease?", "answers": "Stroke is not hereditary, but there are some inherited conditions that can cause stroke. One example is cerebral autosomal dominant arteriopathy with subcortical infarcts and leukoencephalopathy (CADASIL). Read more about it at: http://ghr.nlm.nih.gov/condition/cerebral-autosomal-dominant-arteriopathy-with-subcortical-infarcts-and-leukoencephalopathy"}
{"_id": "87f1525e", "question": "What are foods that prevent heart disease and stroke?", "answers": "20 Foods That Can Help Prevent Heart Disease\n1 – Fresh Herbs\nWhen you add these to foods instead of salt and fat, you’re making a heart-healthy choice. They add flavor without the bad stuff. Spices and other foods are delicious ways to eat heart-smart.\n2 – Black Beans\nMild, tender black beans are packed with heart-healthy nutrients. Folate, antioxidants, and magnesium can help lower blood pressure. Their fiber helps control both cholesterol and blood sugar levels. Add beans to boost soups and salads.\nPrep Tip: Rinse canned beans to remove extra salt.\n3 – Red Wine and Resveratrol\nIf you drink alcohol, a little red wine may be a heart-healthy choice. Resveratrol and catechins, two antioxidants in red wine, may protect artery walls. Alcohol can also boost HDL, the good cholesterol.\nTip: Too much alcohol hurts the heart. Don’t have more than one drink a day for women or two drinks for men. It’s best to talk to your doctor first. Alcohol may cause problems for people taking aspirin and other medications.\n4 – Salmon: Super Food\nA top food for heart health, it’s rich in omega-3s. Omega-3s are healthy fats that may lessen the risk of heart rhythm disorders and lower blood pressure. They may also lower triglycerides and curb inflammation. The American Heart Association recommends two servings of salmon or other oily fish a week.\nCooking Tip: Bake salmon in foil with herbs and veggies. Toss extra cooked salmon in fish tacos and salads.\nBy The Way There is More\nSource: NY Times"}
{"_id": "4b3aff4f", "question": "Is it true that there is no proof of cholesterol lowering drugs lowering the rates of heart attacks and strokes? Instead, there is proof that consuming cholesterol lowering drugs contributes to the risks of having other diseases like diabetes, etc.", "answers": "I am a scientist, and the only thing that matters to me is evidence, and quality of evidence matters most. Although your question is prejudicial, I will try to answer it nevertheless.\nFirstly, there actually is robust evidence that cholesterol lowering drugs, called statins, have a statistically significant causal effect on lowering the risk of cardiovascular disease. A systematic review (considered the pinnacle on the hierarchy of biomedical research\n), published by the Cochrane Collaboration\n, concluded that:\nOf 1000 people treated with a statin for five years, 18 would avoid a major CVD event which compares well with other treatments used for preventing cardiovascular disease. Taking statins did not increase the risk of serious adverse effects such as cancer. Statins are likely to be cost-effective in primary prevention.\nSystematic reviews roll up results from a large number of clinical studies, in this case 19 studies, to remove bias and other issues. In this case, statins clearly save lives.\nFurthermore, the standard of care of most healthcare plans state that aggressively treating cholesterol in patients leads to better outcomes. Which means the healthcare plan is spared the expense of paying for angioplasty, stents, bypass surgery, and other expensive medical procedures.\nAs for stroke, statins have shown no significant causal effect on the risk of stroke. However, modern evidence-based medicine attacks stroke risk independent of cholesterol levels.\nWith respect to adverse effects,\nthere is no robust evidence that supports a causal effect between statin use and diabetes. In fact, diabetes is, in itself, linked to cardiovascular disease.\nthere is no robust evidence of a causal link between statins and cancer.\nthere is some evidence of rare and reversible cognitive decline with the use of statins. Once it is recognized by the physician, the FDA urges that the patient not receive the medication any longer.\nthere is also some evidence of muscle pain with the use of statins. However, there are a lot of confounding factors, like diabetes and high blood pressure, which could be linked to the muscle pain.\nI know it’s cool for some people to criticize the use of statins because of some huge Big Pharma conspiracy. Unfortunately for them, the real scientific and clinical evidence contradicts those claims.\nOh one more thing. Science doesn’t “prove” anything – it makes provisional conclusions based on evidence supporting or nullifying a hypothesis.\nMathematics, albeit a science, uses proofs, which are inferential arguments within a mathematical statement."}
{"_id": "c0f20158", "question": "How do I prevent hypertension, heart disease, diabetes and stroke?", "answers": "IHigh blood pressure is also known as hypertension. Blood pressure is the amount of force exerted by the blood against the walls of the arteries as blood flows through them.\nblood pressure is the most common problem which is faced by 30% of the population of the world.\nIf left untreated or uncontrolled, high blood pressure can cause many health problems. These conditions include heart diseases, vision loss, stroke, and kidney disease ,\nCauses\nThe risk of developing hypertension increases as people age.\nThe heart is a muscle that pumps blood around the body.\nBlood that has low oxygen levels is pumped towards the lungs, where oxygen supplies are replenished. The oxygen rich blood is then pumped by the heart around the body to supply our muscles and cells. The pumping of blood creates pressure.\nIf a person has high blood pressure, it means that the walls of the arteries are receiving too much pressure on a constant basis.\nThe causes of high blood pressure are divided into two categories:\nEssential high blood pressure: This has no established cause.\nSecondary high blood pressure: There is an underlying cause.\nEven though there is no identifiable cause for essential high blood pressure, there is strong evidence linking some risk factors to the likelihood of developing the condition.\nMost of the causes below are risk factors for essential high blood pressure. There are also examples of secondary high blood pressure:\n1) Age\nThe older you are the higher your risk of having high blood pressure. www.healthpot9.blogspot.com"}
{"_id": "41decf4d", "question": "Is a stroke considered coronary artery disease?", "answers": "It is not. Coronary arteries supply blood to the heart tissue only. Strokes occur in the brain, far away from the heart.\nHowever, both result from ischemia in the target organ and are caused by very similar mechanisms of hypertension that primes arteries for atherosclerosis which decreases blood supply to tissues, and unstable plaque, ruptured by hypertension, that then forms a clot which blocks blood delivery to either a part of the brain to provoke a stroke or an area of the heart to provoke a heart attack. Hemorrhagic strokes are also common.\nA stroke is a cerebral artery (cerebrovascular) disease or an ischemic brain disease while a heart attack or angina pectoris is a coronary artery or an ischemic heart disease. Both are cardiovascular diseases as they involve the heart’s action on blood vessels and blood vessel’s impact on the heart’s action."}
{"_id": "7c3493fe", "question": "What type of disease is a stroke?", "answers": "A stroke occurs when a blood vessel in the brain ruptures and bleeds, or when there’s a blockage in the blood supply to the brain. The rupture or blockage prevents blood and oxygen from reaching the brain’s tissues.\nAccording to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), stroke is the fifth-leading trusted Source cause of death in the United States. Every year, more than 795,000Trusted Source U.S. people have a stroke."}
{"_id": "942dd621", "question": "What is the mechanism of action of citicoline? Why is it used in the treatment of Alzheimer's disease and stroke?", "answers": "Citicoline (Cytidine-5′-diphosphocholine or CDP-choline), an intermediate in the biosynthesis of phosphatidylcholine (PtdCho), is one of the cell membrane components that is degraded during cerebral ischaemia to free fatty acids and free radicals.[1]\nIt increase the brain phosphatidylcholine, which is important for brain function. The therapeutic action of citicoline is thought to be caused by stimulation of PtdCho and sphingomyelin synthesis, and by inhibiting the destructive processes (activation of phospholipases)in the ischemic brain[2]\nCiticoline neuroprotection may include-\npreserving cardiolipin (an exclusive inner mitochondrial membrane component) and sphingomyelin;\npreserving the arachidonic acid content of PtdCho and phosphatidylethanolamine;\npartially restoring PtdCho levels;\nstimulating glutathione synthesis and glutathione reductase activity;\nattenuating lipid peroxidation;\nrestoring Na+/K+ATPase activity.[3]\nCiticoline also provides choline for synthesis of neurotransmitter acetylcholine, stimulation of tyrosine hydroxylase activity and dopamine release.\nCiticoline: (a) acetylcholine, PtdCho, AdoMet and GSH biosynthesis and (b)␣sphin- gomyelin synthesis.[4]\nFootnotes\n[1] Cytidinediphosphocholine (CDP-choline) for cognitive and behavioural disturbances associated with chronic cerebral disorders in the elderly.\n[2] Citicoline: neuroprotective mechanisms in cerebral ischemia\n[3] Citicoline: neuroprotective mechanisms in cerebral ischemia\n[4] Citicoline: neuroprotective mechanisms in cerebral ischemia"}
{"_id": "96189589", "question": "What's the point of learning a new language if you can get Alzheimer's disease or have a stroke and lose all of that knowledge?", "answers": "What's the point of being awake? What's the point of knitting? What's the point of cooking? What's the point of a hot bath? What's the point of watching Doctor Who? What's the point of falling in love? What's the point of literally anything?\nThings have value intrinsic to themselves and to you, at that time and place in your life. That they may not be as important in a different time and place in your life is both okay and, I feel that this is important to say, doesn't negate their value they held. They still hold that value, and they always will.\nWhy? Experience changes us. Surely that means something. Experience means the exact people that we influence directly and indirectly are influenced pretty directly by our experiences in life.\nI learned ASL as a Deaf child of 13. From that led to this very moment right now where I'm writing this, fully aware that that choice affected every choice from there. It has meaning and it has value."}
{"_id": "f66ace42", "question": "Can sickle cell disease cause a stroke?", "answers": "Yes lack of oxygen from the sickled red blood cells can cause stroke, children are checked from 2 to 17 to see if they have a propensity for stroke by using transcranial doppler testing. If found that they are likely to having a stroke they begin chronic blood transfusions or blood exchanges in effort to keep the oxygen flowing consistently to the brain."}
{"_id": "301d487a", "question": "Does eating one meal a day cause diabetes, stroke and heart disease?", "answers": "It depends not only on how often you eat, but also in what you eat. If you don’t eat fast-absorbing carbohydrates (as in refined flour, white rice, potatoes) and instead eat fat, protein and fiber rich meals (or slow carbs like in lentils, beans or chick peas), your blood sugar will not have big spike.\nThese foods are also more filling than carbohydrate rich foods and will help control hunger better, not the other way around.\nI would not eat once a day because I like stopping for a meal (and eating) and I don’t see many advantages to eat besides time saving.\nThat being said, the refered article is vague and outdated in my opinion, as it does not make any reference to which kind of diet it is talking about."}
{"_id": "f541e695", "question": "Which autoimmune disease can cause a stroke?", "answers": "Behçet's disease (BD) can cause stroke. It’s a chronic, systemic vasculitis that can cause stroke.\nAny vascular disease affecting multiple systems increases the chance of TIAs or stroke\nOthers include:\nBuerger's Disease (Thromboangiitis Obliterans)\nEosinophilic granulomatosis with polyangiitis (EGPA, formerly known as Churg Strauss)\nCryoglobulinemia.\nGiant Cell Arteritis\nHenoch-Schönlein Purpura\nMicroscopic Polyangiitis\nPolyarteritis Nodosa\nPolymyalgia Rheumatica\nRheumatoid Vasculitis\nTakayasu’s Arteritis\nGranulomatosis with Polyangiitis (GPA, formerly known as Wegener’s)\nI will have missed many other Vasculitis. For instance, Cerebral autosomal dominant arteriopathy with subcortical infarcts and leukoencephalopathy (CADASIL) should be included even though it’s technically not multi-system, but is contained as vasculitis mainly in the brain.\nCerebral Autosomal Dominant Arteriopathy (CADASIL)"}
{"_id": "63653a8b", "question": "My mother's obese. She is a recovering stroke patient and has coronary heart disease. How can I know if she's taken in just enough food in her diet?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "880b45fa", "question": "Is heart stroke a disease?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2e203dbd", "question": "What does it mean to die from heart disease that is not a stroke, when you have diabetes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d6591e54", "question": "How do I avoid heart disease with a long family history of heart attacks and stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "fee9d423", "question": "Why is it that female hormones are thought to protect against heart disease, but to be the cause of strokes?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "cdbb111f", "question": "Can a sudden start to exercise after months of physical inactivity cause a heart disease/stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "00bc0f63", "question": "How do you start to reverse heart disease without risking a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7090387b", "question": "Are there specific CPT codes for stroke and heart disease to report to my insurance company claim that covers stroke and heart disease?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "72612b3d", "question": "Are strokes related to ischemic heart disease?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1c1318b5", "question": "How are hypertension, heart disease, and stroke related?", "answers": ""}
